[upbeat island music]
[欢快的岛屿音乐]
*
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
[both snoring]
[两人都打呼噜]
- Ooh! Oh!
- 哦！哦！
[both snoring]
[两人都打呼噜]
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
呼呼呼！
- Hi.
- 你好。
Gary, I feel funny inside.
加里，我内心觉得很有趣。
- [snores]
- [打鼾]
- Yow!
- 哟！
Hello.
你好。
- [shivering]
- [发抖]
- Gary, there's something
inside of me.
- 加里，有件事
在我里面。
- Meow.
- 喵。
- You see anything?
- 你看到什么了吗？
- [shivering]
- [发抖]
- [screeches]
- [尖叫声]
[screeching]
[尖叫声]
- Uh-oh! Uh-oh! Oh!
- 呃哦！呃-哦！哦！
- [screeching]
- [尖叫声]
- Gary the Snail,
is that any way
- 蜗牛加里，
是这样吗
to treat
an uninvited guest?
治疗
不速之客？
Oh, hello.
哦，你好。
Ooh! That tickles.
哦！那很痒。
More like prickles.
更像是刺。
Hey, I think I'll call you
Prickles.
嘿，我想我会打电话给你
刺。
- [babbles]
- [胡言乱语]
- [laughs]
I see you.
- [笑]
我看到你了。
- [babbles]
- [胡言乱语]
[babbling]
- [grunting]
[胡言乱语]
- [咕哝]
- [babbles]
- [laughs] Okay, okay.
- [胡言乱语]
- [笑] 好吧，好吧。
Enough's enough. It's time
for you to go, little guy.
够了够了。是时候了
让你走吧，小家伙。
I already have a pet--
Gary.
我已经有宠物了——
加里.
I'm afraid I just don't need
another one.
恐怕我只是不需要
另一个。
Whew.
- [sobbing]
呼。
- [抽泣]
- Aw, stop, stop!
- 噢，停下来，停下来！
Oh, Gary, I don't like to hear
the little guy cry.
哦，加里，我不喜欢听
小家伙哭了。
- Meow.
- 喵。
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
- Such a sad story.
- 多么悲伤的故事啊。
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
- Okay, little buddy,
but just for one night.
- 好吧，小伙子，
但只住一晚。
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
- Nighty night,
Prickles.
- 晚安的夜晚，
刺。
- [snores]
- [打鼾]
[all snoring]
[全都打呼噜]
- Huh?
- 啊？
[techno music playing]
[电子音乐播放]
[both babbling and cheering]
[胡言乱语和欢呼声]
[blowing party horns]
[吹响派对号角]
*
[bike horn honks]
[自行车喇叭鸣响]
*
- Wow, a house party
going on of inside me.
- 哇，家庭聚会
我内心正在发生。
Hey, why wasn't I invited?
嘿，为什么我没有被邀请？
[laughs]
I guess I was,
[笑]
我想我是，
since I am the house.
因为我就是房子。
Look, Gary, now we have tons
of prickly new friends.
听着，加里，现在我们有很多
多刺的新朋友。
- Meow, meow.
- 喵，喵。
- Wup-poo. Wup-poo. Wup-poo.
- 呜呜。呜呜。呜呜。
Wup-poo. Wup-poo.
呜呜。呜呜。
[babbling]
[胡说]
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
Oh, my gosh!
哦，天哪！
I completely lost
all track of time.
我彻底迷失了
所有的时间轨迹。
Hey, uh, sorry to be
a party pooper, guys,
嘿，呃，抱歉
派对扫兴者，伙计们，
but I've gotta take a shower
and get ready for work.
但我得去洗个澡
并准备好工作。
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
Guys?
Guy--guys?
伙计们？
盖伊——伙计们？
- [growling]
- [咆哮]
- Gary, calm down.
We're all friends here.
- 加里，冷静点。
我们都是这里的朋友。
- [blows raspberry]
- [吹覆盆子]
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
[meowing]
[喵喵叫]
- Ow!
- 噢！
[gasps]
[groans]
[喘气]
[呻吟]
Open up, Gary.
I'm still in my underwear.
开放，加里。
我还穿着内衣。
Gary, I need to take
a shower.
加里，我需要采取
淋浴。
Oh!
哦！
- I did not need
to see that!
- 我不需要
看到那个！
Ugh!
[grunts]
啊!
[咕哝]
[tires screeching]
[轮胎的尖叫声]
Ahh!
啊！
All right, I guess you guys
will just have to stay
好吧，我猜你们
只得留下来
and go to work with me.
和我一起去上班。
Just keep a low profile
or I could lose my job.
只是保持低调
否则我可能会失去工作。
[whistles]
[口哨声]
- Eh, SpongeBob.
Did ya clean out the--
- 呃，海绵宝宝。
你清理干净了吗——
Sweet Dutchman's ghost!
可爱的荷兰人的鬼魂！
When's the last time
you took a bath, boy-o?
最后一次是什么时候
你洗澡了吗，小伙子？
You're riddled with vermin.
你身上充满了害虫。
- I-I d-d-don't know
what you mean, sir.
- 我-我不知道
你的意思是，先生。
[inhales]
[吸气]
[groans]
[呻吟]
[all babbling]
[全是胡言乱语]
- If customers find out
you're touching patties
- 如果顾客发现
你在碰肉饼
with your wormy hands,
用你长满虫子的手，
the health department will
shut us down for sure.
卫生部门将
肯定会让我们关闭。
- I understand, sir.
- 我明白了，先生。
Mr. Krabs, will you excuse me
for a second?
蟹老板，请原谅我好吗？
一会儿？
Prickles, you heard
my boss.
刺，你听到了吗
我的老板。
I'm sorry, but I'm gonna
have to ask you
对不起，但我会
得问你
and your friends to leave,
please.
和你的朋友离开，
请。
"Squatters rights"?
“占屋者权利”？
What the heck is
squatters rights?
到底是什么
擅自占地者的权利？
- Oh, they're "lawyering" up,
boy-o.
- 哦，他们正在“打律师”，
男孩-o。
They're makin' a legal claim
to keep living in your body.
他们正在提出法律索赔
继续住在你的身体里。
- It's okay, Mr. Krabs,
they're not hurting me.
- 没关系，蟹老板先生，
他们没有伤害我。
- Son, you gotta understand.
- 儿子，你必须明白。
I can't have you work here
我不能让你在这里工作
in your present
filthy "condisherin'."
在你现在的
肮脏的“歧视”。
Oh!
That's the last straw!
哦！
那是最后一根稻草！
Mr. Squid--
- On it, sir.
鱿鱼先生——
- 就这样吧，先生。
Hasta la vista,
worm boy.
哈斯塔拉远景，
虫子男孩。
- And don't come back
until you're dewormed!
- 并且不要回来
直到驱虫完毕！
- [mumbling]
- [咕哝]
- What am I gonna do?
- 我要做什么？
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Hey, SpongeBo--
Whoa!
- 嘿，海绵宝宝--
哇！
I see you've got yourself
我看到你已经找到了自己
a little problem
with the cooties.
有点问题
与虱子。
- Yeah, and I lost
my job over it.
- 是的，我输了
我的工作就在于此。
- Lost your job you say?
- 你说丢了工作？
I might be able
to help you,
我也许可以
来帮助你，
if you can do
something for me.
如果你能做到
给我的东西。
- Anything, Plankton!
Anything!
- 任何事情，浮游生物！
任何事物！
- [chuckles]
Ridding SpongeBob of his worms
- [轻笑]
消灭海绵宝宝身上的虫子
will put him
forever in my debt.
会把他
永远欠我的债。
That secret formula
is good as mine.
那个秘密配方
和我的一样好。
[techno music playing]
[电子音乐播放]
Time to crash
this lousy party.
崩溃的时间到了
这个糟糕的聚会。
Get it? Lousy? Louse?
Oh, I'm good.
得到它？糟糕吗？虱？
哦，我很好。
[roars]
[怒吼]
[all grunting and fighting]
[所有的咕哝和打斗]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[laughs]
[笑]
Whoa!
[babbling and fighting]
哇！
[胡言乱语和打斗]
[groans]
[呻吟]
You're on your own, worm boy.
你只能靠自己了，虫子男孩。
[techno music playing]
[all babbling]
[电子音乐播放]
[全是胡言乱语]
*
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
Ah! [groaning]
啊! [呻吟]
- Hello?
- 你好？
- You gotta help me!
- 你一定要帮我！
- Ah! It's a monster
with SpongeBob's voice!
- 啊！这是一个怪物
海绵宝宝的声音！
- No, no, Patrick, wait,
don't close the--
- 不，不，帕特里克，等等，
不要关闭--
Aw!
噢！
- [whistles]
- Hmm?
- [口哨]
- 嗯？
Squidward. Squidward!
章鱼哥。章鱼哥！
Squidward.
章鱼哥。
- [whistles]
- [口哨]
- I need a hug.
- 我需要一个拥抱。
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
[gasping]
[喘气]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Does that mean no hug?
这是没有拥抱的意思吗？
- There will be no hugs!
- 不会有拥抱！
Get away from me,
you monstrosity!
离我远点，
你这个怪物！
- [gagging]
- [作呕]
[all humming]
[全部嗡嗡声]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
[all humming]
- [groans]
[全部嗡嗡声]
- [呻吟]
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
[all babbling]
[全是胡言乱语]
[dance music playing]
[舞曲演奏]
- [angry babbling]
- [愤怒的胡言乱语]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Well, this my life
from now on, huh?
好吧，这就是我的生活
从现在开始吧？
[laughs]
[笑]
Just call me
SpongeBob WormPants,
只要打电话给我
海绵宝宝蠕虫裤，
'cause that's all I am,
just an apartment for worms.
因为这就是我的全部
只是蠕虫的公寓。
[laughing]
[笑]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
[all babbling and groaning]
[所有胡言乱语和呻吟]
[horn honks]
[喇叭鸣响]
[all babbling]
[全是胡言乱语]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Oh, that's better.
哦，这样好多了。
Looks like I really wormed
my way out of that one.
看来我真的驱虫了
我摆脱那个的方法。
[laughs]
[笑]
- [sniffs]
- [嗅嗅]
Meow!
喵！
- Gary, it feels so good
to be worm free.
- 加里，感觉真好
没有蠕虫。
[techno music playing]
[all babbling]
[电子音乐播放]
[全是胡言乱语]
*
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
SpongeBob!
I need a hug!
海绵宝宝！
我需要一个拥抱！
[silly music]
[愚蠢的音乐]
*
- [babbles]
- [胡言乱语]
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[mumbling]
[咕哝]
[babbles]
[胡言乱语]
Hmm?
唔？
- [caws]
- [叫声]
- [babbles]
- [胡言乱语]
- [caws]
- [叫声]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[babbling]
[胡说]
[groans and pants]
[呻吟和裤子]
Whew!
[grunts] Ahh.
哇！
[咕噜声]啊。
- [cawing]
- [呱呱叫]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- [babbles] Hmm.
- [胡言乱语] 嗯。
- [caws]
- [screams]
- [叫声]
- [尖叫]
- [snickers]
- [窃笑]
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
- [sniffs]
- [嗅嗅]
[caws]
- [whistling]
[叫声]
- [吹口哨]
[groans]
[呻吟]
[grumbles]
[抱怨]
- [caws]
- [叫声]
- [babbles]
- [胡言乱语]
[growls]
[咆哮]
- [snickers]
- [窃笑]
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
- [cawing]
- [呱呱叫]
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
[babbles]
[胡言乱语]
Hmm.
[chuckles]
唔。
[笑声]
[surprised babble]
[惊讶的胡言乱语]
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
[gasps]
[喘气]
[ominous music]
[不祥的音乐]
[gulps]
[吞咽]
- [growling]
- [咆哮]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- [roars]
- [咆哮]
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
[whimpering]
[babbles]
[胡言乱语]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Ooh!
哦！
[babbles]
[胡言乱语]
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
*